<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Visual WebGUI &#8212; Uh? Neat technology for someone else.	</title>
	<atom:link href="blog/index.php/archives/426/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/index.php/archives/426</link>
	<description>Yet another tech blog.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2009 19:14:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: sandrar		</title>
		<link>/blog/index.php/archives/426/comment-page-1#comment-2739</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sandrar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2009 19:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/index.php/archives/426#comment-2739</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hi! I was surfing and found your blog post... nice! I love your blog.  :) Cheers! Sandra. R.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi! I was surfing and found your blog post&#8230; nice! I love your blog.  :) Cheers! Sandra. R.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: navot		</title>
		<link>/blog/index.php/archives/426/comment-page-1#comment-489</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[navot]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 11:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/index.php/archives/426#comment-489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thanks for publishing and referring to my comment.
 As a framework, developed &#039;with the community and for the community&#039;, not as a slogan but as a strategy, and quick look at our forum will confirm it, we are quite sensitive to the community reactions. In this respect, we take yours as one and ask you, what would look reasonable price for you? Take into account the tremendous saving in developing time that we are perusing and our &#039;Money back Guarantee&#039; offered if you didn&#039;t save twice our price in the first year. 
There is one more correction I should point out; we are not charging for bug fixing. We schedule bugs, sharing our issue tracker scheduling with the community, allowing the community to influence priority with a certain cost. In other words if our original prioritization fits one&#039;s needs, just wait and get your bug fixed, if you want to change priority, that costs. I believe we had strightened another issue.
As for the 20,000 applications. 
We had almost 300,000 downloads since we aired our solution around 20 months ago. We have 23,000 developers/ development shops registered with us which are actually hard working developing VWG applications. A lot of them in production. 
We know it is hard to believe and behind any expectations, but that is reality. Developers loved the solution. One of the development shops, a Canadian for example, is developing its 15th VWG application, SAP its 4th, Israeli Aerospace Industry its second, leading bank in Argentina its second, Israeli Ayalon and Phoenix insurance, IBM GTU its 6th, Canadian ministry of education, Israel ministry of interior, IDF, Blue Phoenix, Net size, File NET, Network D, One human Family... and so on and on… Yes, 20,000 VWG applications! are very conservative estimation based on our support figures and actual licensed customers… many are, by the way, LGPL.
 And here comes the big surprise, things are apperantally,  changing and some of those above (I will not be more specific publicly for understandable reasons) use VWG under LGPL.
I believe your orginization might find it usefull to ask some of those mentioned above about thier considerations in using LGPL. I will be happy to share contacts with you, under more discrete communication such as email. 

Thanks again and keep up the good work
Navot peled]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thanks for publishing and referring to my comment.<br />
 As a framework, developed &#8216;with the community and for the community&#8217;, not as a slogan but as a strategy, and quick look at our forum will confirm it, we are quite sensitive to the community reactions. In this respect, we take yours as one and ask you, what would look reasonable price for you? Take into account the tremendous saving in developing time that we are perusing and our &#8216;Money back Guarantee&#8217; offered if you didn&#8217;t save twice our price in the first year.<br />
There is one more correction I should point out; we are not charging for bug fixing. We schedule bugs, sharing our issue tracker scheduling with the community, allowing the community to influence priority with a certain cost. In other words if our original prioritization fits one&#8217;s needs, just wait and get your bug fixed, if you want to change priority, that costs. I believe we had strightened another issue.<br />
As for the 20,000 applications.<br />
We had almost 300,000 downloads since we aired our solution around 20 months ago. We have 23,000 developers/ development shops registered with us which are actually hard working developing VWG applications. A lot of them in production.<br />
We know it is hard to believe and behind any expectations, but that is reality. Developers loved the solution. One of the development shops, a Canadian for example, is developing its 15th VWG application, SAP its 4th, Israeli Aerospace Industry its second, leading bank in Argentina its second, Israeli Ayalon and Phoenix insurance, IBM GTU its 6th, Canadian ministry of education, Israel ministry of interior, IDF, Blue Phoenix, Net size, File NET, Network D, One human Family&#8230; and so on and on… Yes, 20,000 VWG applications! are very conservative estimation based on our support figures and actual licensed customers… many are, by the way, LGPL.<br />
 And here comes the big surprise, things are apperantally,  changing and some of those above (I will not be more specific publicly for understandable reasons) use VWG under LGPL.<br />
I believe your orginization might find it usefull to ask some of those mentioned above about thier considerations in using LGPL. I will be happy to share contacts with you, under more discrete communication such as email. </p>
<p>Thanks again and keep up the good work<br />
Navot peled</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Aaron		</title>
		<link>/blog/index.php/archives/426/comment-page-1#comment-483</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2008 01:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/index.php/archives/426#comment-483</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[@Navot --
Thanks for the comment. LGPL/GPL doesn&#039;t work for many organizations, including the one that pays my salary for many good reasons (especially ISVs). It&#039;s one of the most confounding/confusing licensing available for open source developers. MIT/BSD -- those are friendly terms (and easily understood by even a layman).

However, I stand by my comments regarding the excessive cost of this toolkit -- it&#039;s well beyond reasonable -- and I understand you need to make a living. Rather than pricing it like a Bentley automobile, you might consider at least dropping it into Mercedes range....

Where do get the 20,000 applications figure?

Like I said, it&#039;s a neat technical achievement. It may fit some needs, but with my architect hat on, it&#039;s not a good fit for many.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>@Navot &#8212;<br />
Thanks for the comment. LGPL/GPL doesn&#8217;t work for many organizations, including the one that pays my salary for many good reasons (especially ISVs). It&#8217;s one of the most confounding/confusing licensing available for open source developers. MIT/BSD &#8212; those are friendly terms (and easily understood by even a layman).</p>
<p>However, I stand by my comments regarding the excessive cost of this toolkit &#8212; it&#8217;s well beyond reasonable &#8212; and I understand you need to make a living. Rather than pricing it like a Bentley automobile, you might consider at least dropping it into Mercedes range&#8230;.</p>
<p>Where do get the 20,000 applications figure?</p>
<p>Like I said, it&#8217;s a neat technical achievement. It may fit some needs, but with my architect hat on, it&#8217;s not a good fit for many.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: navot		</title>
		<link>/blog/index.php/archives/426/comment-page-1#comment-482</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[navot]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2008 13:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/index.php/archives/426#comment-482</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I must say, really enjoyed reading your post... but I don&#039;t count, I am deeply involved with VWG and I love this framework.
I do believe that your readers would like to know, what unfortunately you had missed - VWG is an open source framework, designed to enable Microsoft developers and in particular WinForms&#039;s , to develop HTML or Silverlight front ends FREE OF CHARGE under LGPL / GPL open source license. 
We invested our at most efforts and resources, to develop one of the simplest RAD for web development. We let developers use their existing skill sets and experience, without really needing to relearn and retool, most of them do it without our support. And indeed more then 20,000 applications were developed worldwide (HTML), without or with very little help from us.
So considering the above your cost reference, doesn&#039;t really make much sense.
By the way if you want your readers to know where it is going to cost them (and it is, we have to make our living somehow ), we are going to charge for premiums, leaving the standard 60 out of the box WinForms controls  free of charge to live happily ever after….
To get an idea of the said premiums (in shape of extensions) your readers might be interested in this link:

http://www.visualwebgui.com/Community/Resources/News/tabid/328/articleType/ArticleView/articleId/266/Updated-extensions-business-model.aspx

Thanks
Navot]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I must say, really enjoyed reading your post&#8230; but I don&#8217;t count, I am deeply involved with VWG and I love this framework.<br />
I do believe that your readers would like to know, what unfortunately you had missed &#8211; VWG is an open source framework, designed to enable Microsoft developers and in particular WinForms&#8217;s , to develop HTML or Silverlight front ends FREE OF CHARGE under LGPL / GPL open source license.<br />
We invested our at most efforts and resources, to develop one of the simplest RAD for web development. We let developers use their existing skill sets and experience, without really needing to relearn and retool, most of them do it without our support. And indeed more then 20,000 applications were developed worldwide (HTML), without or with very little help from us.<br />
So considering the above your cost reference, doesn&#8217;t really make much sense.<br />
By the way if you want your readers to know where it is going to cost them (and it is, we have to make our living somehow ), we are going to charge for premiums, leaving the standard 60 out of the box WinForms controls  free of charge to live happily ever after….<br />
To get an idea of the said premiums (in shape of extensions) your readers might be interested in this link:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.visualwebgui.com/Community/Resources/News/tabid/328/articleType/ArticleView/articleId/266/Updated-extensions-business-model.aspx" rel="nofollow ugc">http://www.visualwebgui.com/Community/Resources/News/tabid/328/articleType/ArticleView/articleId/266/Updated-extensions-business-model.aspx</a></p>
<p>Thanks<br />
Navot</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
